<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vijay's Website</title>
    <description>A minimalist Jekyll theme</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Teaching Assistantship for CS 18000 - Object Oriented Programming</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;During the Fall semester 2019, I worked as an undergraduate teaching assistant for the introductory computer science class for CS majors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My roles included proctoring exams and lab sessions, as well as answering student questions on Piazza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building off my experience as a teaching assistant for CS 177, I worked individually with students to clarify concepts explained in lecture and answer questions peratining to the lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve explained syntatic parts of java, like case statements and GUI’s, to complex aspects of languages, including syncrhonization, and the four pillars of object-oriented programming (Abstraction, Inheritance, Encapsulation, and Polymorphism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;testimonials&quot;&gt;Testimonials&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always a joy to work with new students and aid their understanding. Here are some reviews that I received from students during that semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is always very quick to come help if I have a question or am stuck in a part of the lab. Always able to communicate why something isn’t working and lead me to solution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Great at debugging and very helpful with issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Helpful with easy to understand explanations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Always here on time and helpful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://localhost:4000/CS180TAShip</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/CS180TAShip</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>UPS Internship</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Internship season was difficult as a freshman. At career fairs, recruiters would often dismiss my skills and abilities upon hearing the number of years I had spent in college. Fortunately, one company acknowledged my skills during career fair and interview process - UPS.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
          <pubDate>2019-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://localhost:4000/UPSInternship</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/UPSInternship</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Teaching Assistantship for CS 17700 - Programming with Multimedia Objects</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;During the first week of Spring semester of 2019, I approached my professor to become a teaching assistant for the Python class that I took. One week later, I attended a lab session for my first teaching assistant position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My roles included proctoring lab session, grading lab assignments, and proctoring office hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience taught me much about being a teaching assistant. To start, I learned to guide students to their solutions without directly giving them answers. I worked on my teaching technique each time I was approached with a problem during one of my three lab sessions or office hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holding office hours also taught me how to manage my time with multiple students. During the nights before the projects were due, office hours would be packed full of students. I had to spend no more than 5 minutes or less with each student answering their questions or debugging their code. Overall, this improved my ability to debug quickly and answer questions rapidly. A tiresome process, but ultimately, a rewarding one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;testimonials&quot;&gt;Testimonials&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being my first semester as a Teaching Assistant, I received encouraging reviews from my students. Here are some of the reviews that I received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When he did come to answer questions, he was helpful and tried his best to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The instructor answered questions well, and was very helpful in doing such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In lab, you were helpful whenever students had questions. You explained the labs well and were patient with every student. Night office hours were also extremely helpful, thanks!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2019-01-11T00:00:00-08:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://localhost:4000/CS177TAShip</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/CS177TAShip</guid>
        </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
